# Adam Makaoui

Victoria, BC | 250-266-6856 | csuvic@uvic.ca | linkedin.com/in/adam-makaoui/ | github.com/Adam-Makaoui

# **Summary of Qualifications**

Languages	<b>Software Tools</b>	<b>Technical Skills</b>	Soft skills
<ul><li>Java</li><li>HTML/XML</li><li>JSON</li><li>SQL</li><li>Python</li><li>C</li></ul>	<ul> <li>Linux terminal</li> <li>Servers &amp; VMs</li> <li>Git/Version control</li> <li>Docker</li> <li>APIs/REST</li> <li>Databases</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Code Debugging</li> <li>OOP &amp; OOD</li> <li>Documentation</li> <li>Scripting (Bash/Py.)</li> <li>Software Testing</li> <li>Data Structures</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Attention to detail</li> <li>Quick Learning</li> <li>Problem Solving</li> <li>Communication</li> <li>Collaboration &amp; Teamwork</li> <li>Research &amp; Self-Learning</li> </ul>

#### **Education**

*Majoring in Computer Science* (Software Engineering Specialization) University of Victoria, Victoria, BC

(Year 3) 2019 - 2020

Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Databases, Software Engineering, Computer architecture.

Economic Analysis & Computing (Interdisciplinary Studies)

2014 - 2018

Western University, London, ON

Coursework: Systems programming, Web design, Data Visualization, Finance/Economics, Mathematics.

## **Relevant Experience**

Software Engineer – Nokia (Ottawa, ON)

Sept 2019. - Dec. 2019

- Delivered upgrades to the patch page by working on the legacy code of the patch system in Perl, html.
- Developed features and fixes for an XML to JSON software code converter tool.

**Software Documenter – Lumberworld** (Victoria, BC)

June 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Documented the code base by providing the purpose, framework, structure, functionality, and tools used for the swift project, an online market place.
- Performed error checking and formatting before exporting the code into a word document for printing.

#### Hackathon Event Staff – Hack Western (London, ON)

Nov. 2018

- Articulated the hackathon event handling the front stations, aiding 700+ participates.
- Toke a leadership role managing 3 other Event Staff in the implementation of a framework I suggested.

#### Computer & Office Assistant – Western University (London, ON)

July 2018 – Aug. 2018

- Installed all hardware and maintain and updated software for 80+ PCs for two labs in under a week.
- Articulated tests on all machines for bugs and faults, 3 software & 2 hardware faults were identified.

#### **Personal Projects**

GitHub: github.com/Adam-Makaoui | Website: github.com/Adam-Makaoui

- Dicee is a mobile application which simulates dice rolls. There are two dice on the screen and each of them (images) are updated based on the randomly generated numbers. May 2019
- Personal Website is my own website created entirely in HTML. It serves as a basic portfolio source to gain information about myself. It contains audio, images, hyperlinks, and other HTML components. **April 2019**
- SecretMessageApp is a mobile application which encodes a string of text by using the Caesar's cipher method of shifting each letter by a factor. The encoded text can be decode using the same key used to scramble it.
- **RecordStack** is a desktop software used to store and manipulate data. RecordStack allows the user to insert, delete, find, and display all records and the number of contents contained in it.
- Ticktacktoe is a classic game which includes an interactive GUI and AI. The difficulty & size of the board can be adjusted. A toggleable option exists to play the game even after a tie by moving blocks around.

## Achievements, Certification, and Training

- **Udemy**: Completion of Android Development and Unity game design course.
- **SoloLearn**: Completion of Java, C, HTML courses.
- Certificate of Academic Engagement (Western University, 2018)

UVic Co-op Program